## HIEN NGUYEN

# **Software Engineer**

Englewood, NJ 07631 | 551-241-1281 | thuhiennguyen198@gmail.com

Github | AngelList | LinkedIn

Software Engineering professional with nearly ten years of experience in education and customer service. After transitioning to the US, I made the decision to shift into the more creative and challenging space of tech. I have spent the past year learning the necessary technologies and skills to be a strong developer and utilize my former experience to work collaboratively, learn quickly, and communicate strongly. Given my abilities, I am now ready and eager to start contributing to an innovative company as a software engineer.

#### SKILLS

Java, Spring MVC Framework, SpringBoot, JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, Webpack, jQuery, Git, Heroku

#### **PROJECTS**

Cat Academy | (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Canvas API, Webpack, PostgreSQL)

github repo

Interactive typing game, based on the 4 Degrees of Typer Shark Deluxe game

- Implemented HTML Canvas to dynamically render 2D shapes to create a visually compelling game character.
- Built custom game logic using the Async/Await pattern and Promises that manage the current state of play and give updates on current user scores.
- Generated random words using the "random-words" package, kept tracking players' scores to render more words, and leveled up the game.

**Homi** | (React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Webpack, Amazon S3, Heroku) github repo Homi, an Esty.com clone, is an online e-commercial platform where independent artists and crafters can sell their goods.

- Designed a search feature that pulls results from the PostgreSQL database allowing users to filter by keyword.
- Incorporated Amazon S3's data storage infrastructure to upload and retrieve files, benefiting from its data scalability and capacity, resulting in improved page-load performance.
- Utilized Bcrypt to hash and salt passwords, strengthening the protection of user data with secure authentication.

Around the block (React, Redux, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS3, Heroku) github repo

Around the block, a social-media app for seniors to find companies for their daily activities by joining and creating events.

- Collaborated with team members using Git workflow and Slack to achieve features in a timely manner, while switching between both frontend and backend.
- Leveraged JSON Web Token, MongoDB/Express, and React modal components for user authentication.
- Implemented Voice-to-text API to facilitate users a more convenient experience navigating the app.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer Apprenticeship | App Academy

Server team lead | N2M LLC

Customer Service Representative | Suzuki Sai Gon Ngoi Sao JSC

Aug 2022 - Present

Nov 2018 - Dec 2020

Nov 2013 - June 2016

### **EDUCATION**

**AppAcademy** - Highly selective web development program with a 3% acceptance rate **Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology and Education** - BS Education

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021 Sep 2009 - Jan 2014